

• sierramatice.karras@gmail.com • sierramatice.github.io/portfolio • linkedin.com/in/sierramatice-karras •

Professional Summary

I am a UX generalist, specializing in UX and UI Research, Design, and Prototyping. I am interested in both the research and design side of UX and UI, as well as the opportunity to develop solutions to existing and emerging issues within projects.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Human Centered Design and Engineering

Grad June 2019

University of Washington

- → Minor in Urban Ecological Design
- → Dean's List

Experience

UX Designer and Researcher

June 2016 — Present

UW Clinical Informatics Research Group

- → Design and prototyping of web layout and navigation
- → Conducting heuristic and interview based usability studies
- → Researching and creating design best practices + reference documents
- → QA testing for a wide number of clinical systems
- → Key Skills: Usability Research, HTML, Wireframing, Interaction Design, Web Design

Lead Designer and Prototyper, Co-Lead of Research and Evaluation

Jan 2019 — Oct 2019

CoMotion Mobility Innovation Center, King County Metro, Sound Transit HCDE Senior Capstone Project—People's Choice Award Winner

- → Coordinated with, presented to and collaborated with project sponsors
- → Researched and Evaluated the user experience of existing systems
- → Designed and built the interactive prototype of our recommended solution
- → Key Skills: Visual Design, Interaction Design, Prototyping, User Research, Usability Research

Freelance Designer

Jan 2015 — Oct 2019

- → Designed unique products and logos for client's needs
- → Prototyped using 3D modeling, laser cutting, and paper prototyping
- → Utilized a variety of design software to best fit each project
- → Key Skills: Creative Design, Interaction Design, Prototyping, Product Design, Communication

Vice Chair and Voting Committee Member

Sep 2015 — Aug 2017

UW Campus Sustainability Fund

- → Reviewed and coached sustainability projects applying for funding
- → Assisted in management and budgeting of over \$300,000 a year
- → Collaborated on interviewing and hiring new committee members
- → Key Skills: Project Management, Leadership, Strategic Thinking

Additional Skills

• User Experience (UX) Design • User Experience (UX) Research • Rapid Prototyping • Interactive Prototyping • Paper Prototyping • Wireframing • User Testing • Low to High Fidelity Mockups • Design Thinking • Graphic Design • Mobile Design • Designing for Kids • Visual Communication • Physical Prototyping • 3D Modeling • Human Computer Interaction • Information Visualization •